Kaiji challenged the director
to a final gamble.
カイジは黒幕会長に
最後の勝負を挑んだ
The director accepts,
but only with three conditions.
会長は勝負の受諾と引き換えに
ある提案をする
One of them is
a wager of 100 million.
それは掛け金１億の勝負
カイジが賭けるものは
2000万と指４本
Kaiji's wager comprises of
20 million and four of his fingers!
100 million.
A staggering amount!
１億
圧倒的な金それが目の前
つかめば届く所にある
The money is before his eyes
and within his reach.
However...
ただし
His fingers are at stake
if he loses!
負ければ持っていかれるこの指
根元から４本
They will be excised at the root!
さあ
どうする？カイジ君
So, what will it be, Kaiji?
Not only will I lose my fingers,
指をなくす上に2000万も取られ
but I'll lose
the 20 million too...
All that will remain
are debts and pain.
残るのは借金と痛み
壊滅的敗北
A complete utter defeat.
手持ちの2000万が
みすぼらしく見えちまう大金
That huge amount makes
my 20 million look shabby.
時給900円の俺が
どんだけ働いても
With my hourly pay of 900 yen,
I'll never attain it.
No matter how hard I work.
働いても
たどり着けない金
I'll never achieve that amount.
これだけあればやり直せる
With this, I can start all over!
I can start over from
the beginning!
全てを
最初から
俺の願い通りの人生にやり直せる
I can rebuild my life again
just the way I want it.
いけ　怖いのは
Go for it!
The only thing to fear...
...is if he draws the winning lot
on the first try!
やつが１回目に
当たりを引いてしまうこと
ありえないことじゃないが
限りなく０に近い確率
It's not entirely impossible but
he has almost no chance of that.
As long as I don't get unlucky,
I'm sure to win this!
そんな不運さえなければ
勝てる
勝てるんだ
I can win!
カイジさん
Kaiji...
大丈夫だ
いける
It's fine. I'll do it.
でも
いいんだ
- B-But!
- It'll be fine!
If you lose...
もし負けたら
それは考えないわけじゃねえ
It's true that it's not
entirely impossible.
負ける不運を
まるで考えないわけじゃねえ
けど
It's not entirely impossible
to suffer bad luck.
However...
この俺の人生を
完全に塗り替えられる
I can repaint my life again
from scratch!
これだけの金を目の前にして
The money to do so
is right before my eyes!
降りられるか
Can I let it pass by?
ＧＯだ
Go!
ざわ
ざわー
Investment
ＧＯだ
俺は指を賭ける
Go!
I'll bet my fingers!
ざわ
Indeed, spoken like a
young man pursuing his dream.
それでこそ夢を追う若者だ
素晴らしい
Excellent!
飛んだぞ眠気が
I'm not sleepy anymore!
おかげで覚醒した
I'm now fully awake!
They're dancing,
my aging cells are dancing!
踊る
この老いぼれの細胞が踊る
脳を
ベータエンドルフィンが駆け巡る
My beta-endorphins are
pumping madly within my brain!
活性化する
It's a revival!
Thank you, I'm truly grateful...
ありがたい
これぞ長寿の秘訣
This is the secret to longevity!
ざわ
これ
何をしておる
What are you doing?
Get started!
用意だ
はい
Y-Yes, Sir!
さっさとせんか
グズが
Hurry it up, slow coach!
セット完了
これでもう動かせない
Everything is ready!
There's no backing out now.
カイジの左手は
指先がわずかに動かせるだけ
Kaiji can barely move
his fingers.
あはは　狂気の沙汰
This is madness!
考えてみればつくづく狂気の沙汰
This is a state of madness,
however you look at it!
Don't you think so?
そうは思わんか
We're betting on
frail slips of paper...
吹けば飛ぶようなそんな紙くず
...that would fly away
at the slightest breeze.
即席のそんなくじに
かたや１億
With a wager of
100 million on one side...
...and 20 million plus
four fingers on the other.
かたや指４本と2000万を
賭けようというのだ
No doubt about it,
this is bizarre!
間違いなく常軌を逸しておる
しかし快感は
本当のめくるめく快感は
But doing this feels
truly wonderful.
常軌を逸するからこそ
たどり着ける
One can only feel like this
during extreme situations!
カイジ君は
もうそのことを知っておろう
Kaiji, I'm sure you've
experienced it too, right?
のう
You crossed the bridge
and survived.
橋を渡りきっての生き残り
Ｅカードの勝利
You won in E-Card.
That moment of
happiness and relief...
その瞬間の歓喜
安堵
快感は強烈だったはず
...must have been one
of heightened pleasure.
死の際の生は苦しくとも充実し
Near-death instances
are painful, but satisfying.
And the experience of surviving
each time is simply sweet.
またそこからの生還は
この世のものとは思えぬほど甘美
Absolute bliss!
圧倒的至福
その快感に
もうカイジ君の脳は焼かれた
The experience of that pleasure
has taken over your mind.
恐らく
これからのカイジ君の人生は
From now on, you will
probably live your life...
その快感を追い続ける人生になる
...pursuing excitement
of that nature.
そういう意味では
仮にここで１億を手にしても
Even if you win this match
to obtain 100 million,
your addiction to that ecstasy...
いずれその快感に身を任せ
ギャンブルの闇に消える金
...would cause you to gamble
that money away.
それがジャンキーの性
That's the life of an addict.
あーははははは
違うな
You're wrong.
もう懲り懲りさ
こんな地獄めぐりはもう懲り懲り
I've had enough.
I'm sick of
gambling my life away.
俺はもしここで勝ったら
きっちり足を洗う
If I win, I'll wash my
hands off gambling completely.
だからこれが最後
That's why this is the last...
My last gamble ever!
本当に最後のギャンブル
I'll survive and return.
もう生還する
俺は生還する
I'm going to reclaim my life
from this never ending nightmare!
終わらない悪夢から
ほう　ふはは　はははははは
Place the money
on top of his 100 million.
金を置いてくれ
やつの１億の上に
はい
Okay!
総額１億2000万
A total sum of 120 million!
あの
- Hey...
- Yeah?
正確には2010万あって
Actually, there's 20.1 million.
だからその10万余分っていうか
So, there's 100,000 extra.
やるよ
Take it.
10万にとどまらねえ
It won't just be 100,000.
勝ったら
皆にはそれなりに配って回る
If I win, I'll give everyone
a substantial amount.
You guys have helped me a lot,
especially with the treatment.
治療やら何やら
いろいろ世話になったからな
また世話になるかもしれんしの
You'll probably
need their help again.
また
治療やら何やら
You'd need help
for first aid, that is.
ざわ
ではそろそろ始めるかの
Alright.
Shall we begin?
そこに積まれた１億
万を
カイジ君が持って帰るか
You'll either bring back the
120 million from this gamble...
それともそれを果たせず
指を失うかもしれぬギャンブルを
...or fail, and lose your
fingers as a result.
じゃあ
待った
Well then...
Wait!
それは
Should we place that winning lot
into the box together?
その当たりくじだけは
２人で入れようじゃないか
I'd be in trouble if you
hid it elsewhere...
入れたふりをして
どこかに忍ばされても困る
...while pretending to put it in.
馬鹿な
そんなこと
That's crazy!
He wouldn't stoop so low!
いや
ありうる
No, that's a possibility.
I didn't realise
until he said it.
言われりゃその通り
気がつかなかった
ははは　では
Alright then.
Wait!
待った
くじに触れる前に
Before touching the lot,
その手に何も
仕込まれていないことを証明しろ
you must prove that you've
nothing else in that hand.
これはまた用心深い
How wary of you.
That goes without saying!
当たり前だ
ほれ
いいかなあ
これで
Here. Are you satisfied?
Yeah.
じゃあ俺も
Now, it's my turn.
あはは　ＯＫ
ＯＫ
Okay, fine.
You don't have to do that.
そんなことせずとも
わしゃカイジ君を信用しとるよ
I trust you, Kaiji.
Well then, now that neither
of us have a problem...
では互いに問題のないところで
当たりくじを箱へ
The winning ticket
goes into the box!
投入
It is released!
はっ　では
Okay.
Will that do?
いいかな
Yeah.
ではこちらのくじも入れます
Now, I'll place the
other lots inside.
混ぜます
Shuffling.
大丈夫
これくらいなら落ちないはずだ
It'll be fine.
That shouldn't cause it
to slip out.
落ちなければ俺の勝ち
If it didn't fall out, I'll win.
落ちなければ
As long as it doesn't slip out...
As long as it doesn't!
It's fine. What he did wasn't
enough to make it slip!
大丈夫
これくらいなら落ちない
It hasn't fallen out.
The setup is still intact!
落ちていない
仕込みは残っている
After this...
あとは
この男が一発で引かなければ
If he fails on
the first attempt...
勝ち　勝ち　勝ち　勝ち
I'll win.
I'll win!
ではまずわしから
So, I'll be making
the first draw!
１回目
これか
The director makes his pick.
会長
選択
引くな
Don't draw it!
何でもいい
ともかくここ一度だけ
Just draw a blank one.
Don't draw the winning lot!
引くな
引かなければ勝てる
As long as he
doesn't draw it, I can win!
勝てるんだ
I can win!
えーと
どこじゃろかい
Where could it be?
Don't draw it!
引くな
どこじゃろかいな
Where are you?
神よ！
Please, god!
その時
トイレに残り
他のティッシュ箱に
At that time, No.5 who
remained in the toilet...
...to dispose of the rest
of the lots, returns.
仕込んだくじを処理した
５番も戻ってくる
But he's not the only one
to return.
戻ってきたのは彼だけではない
彼の後ろに十数人の男たち
About 10 other men
followed behind.
そう
１番目の橋で落ちた
重傷者たちである
Indeed, they fell off
the first bridge...
...and are now badly injured.
Those watching Kaiji's game
suffered less severe injuries.
カイジの戦いを見ていたのは
比較的軽傷の者たちであった
重傷者たちは部屋の外から
中をうかがっていたのだが
The others had been watching
from outside the room,
but they now crawled forward
to Kaiji's side.
彼らも
はい進み
カイジのそばに集まる
そう
共有するために
Yes, they wanted a part
in this experience.
A part of Kaiji's anxiety,
uncertainty and prayers...
カイジの不安と葛藤
祈り
And if he wins,
they want to share his joy!
そして
もし勝ったならば
歓喜を共有するために
考えてみれば
カイジと彼らは皆
似た者同士
Thinking about it, Kaiji is
in the same boat as them.
皆似たような過ちを犯し
Everyone made the same mistakes
and left behind a trail of debts.
多額の借金を背負い
現在は
はいつくばるような日々
They lead meaningless lives.
焦燥と失意と後悔
They feel impatience,
lost and regret.
They lead lives of distress.
苦汁の日々
And they yearn
to be free again.
そこからの脱皮
離脱
瞬間的離脱は
彼らの夢であり
カイジの夢
They dream of instant escape
from that way of life.
Kaiji is similar.
それが今
最も分かりやすい形で
達成されようとしている
All that is now happening...
...in the most
straightforward way possible!
If I win,
I'll gain 120 million!
勝てば 億　１億2000万
カイジさん
- Kaiji...
勝てば
再生
If I win, I'll start afresh!
Everything would have
been worth it!
全てが報われる
Ishida...
石田さん
佐原
Sahara...
Also, I'll be able
to rebuild my life.
そしてやり直せる
人生
俺の人生
My life!
Oh my...
おや
Oh my, oh my, oh my!
Kaiji, this is the most
frightening part...
カイジ君
これだから
ここ一番の熱い勝負は恐ろしい
...of a gambling match.
往々にして不可思議な
まず起こりえないことが起こる
Now and then,
strange occurences...
...which should not occur
start taking place.
通常のはかりを超えてな
It goes beyond
normal calculations.
ざわ
ざわー
まさか
D-Don't tell me!
本当に
当たりを
Don't tell me,
he actually got it!
He drew the winning lot
in just one try?!
当たりくじを一発で
カイジ君
Kaiji, this is the terrifying part
of a one-round gamble.
これが一発勝負の怖いところじゃ
ほれ
ざわ
See?
きさま
Darn it!
不思議じゃろ
Well? Mysterious, isn't it?
わしのような王が一発で引けぬ
Even a king like me couldn't
draw it on my first attempt.
そんな理不尽が
起こってしまうのだ
Such illogical things
do occur...
...in a one-round
match like this.
ここ一発の勝負では
ざわ
ざわー
こいつふざけやがって
He was mocking me!
That was a deliberate attempt
to harrass me!
性質の悪い嫌がらせだ
何が
わしのような王が
死にぞこないが
What did that dotard mean
by "a king like me"?!
Kaiji curses the director
inwardly.
カイジ
心中で毒づく
だがそんな怒りも一瞬
But his anger is only fleeting.
すぐに別の圧倒的感情が
押し寄せてくる
Soon, he will be overwhelmed
by a variety of other emotions.
He would be embraced with
relief, great joy and happiness!
安堵
歓喜
至福
そんな思いが全身を包む
そう
引かなかった
Indeed, he did not draw it.
What matters is that the director
did not draw the winning lot!
会長は当たりくじを引かなかった
それが全て
カイジの勝利
もう目前！
Kaiji could see his victory!
片手じゃ持ちにくい
持ってくれるか
It's hard to hold the box
with one hand.
Could you hold it for me?
はい
Y-Yes!
へへへ　どうぞどうぞ
Be my guest.
分かってるな
You get it, right?
俺が当たりを引いたら
おまえは派手に喜べ
When I draw the winning lot,
you'll make a big show of it.
箱を引っちゃぶき
Tip the box upside down,
中にあるもう１枚の当たりを
床にばらまき
and scatter the remaining lot
with those on the floor.
うやむやにする
俺の左手が固定されている今
それはおまえの役目
With my left hand strapped tight,
it's all up to you.
I got it, Kaiji.
分かってますってカイジさん
そんなの箱を持てって
言われた時から察してます
I understood the moment
I was asked to hold the box...
大丈夫
任せてください
Don't worry, leave it to me!
Great.
よし
これで
With this...
With this... I'll win!
これで勝ち
これで
With this,
I'll get 100 million!
１億
あれ
おかしいな
Huh?
That's strange!
くじを仕込んだのは
こっち側だと思ってたが
I remember putting the
fake lot on this side.
ないってことは逆だったか
手前か
If it's not here, it must be
on the other side...
In front of me?
I-Impossible!
Where is it?!
馬鹿な
何でないんだ
どうして　そんな
Why?! No way...
It's impossible!
そんなことがあるか
やっぱり向こう側だ
さっきはつい見つけ損ねただけで
It must be on the other side!
Maybe I overlooked it earlier.
どうして
奥か
W-Why?!
Is it further inside?
Did I unknowingly push it
further in with my finger?!
さっき知らずに指で
奥に
奥に押し込んでしまったのか
K-Kaiji?
カイジさん？
It's gone!
ない
ない！
落ちてしまったのか
Did it fall while being
brought here from the toilet?
さっきトイレから持ってきた時か
シャッフルしている時に
Or maybe during
the shuffling?
カイジさん
Kaiji...
Kaiji!
引くしかない
I've no choice but to draw...
九分九厘勝つギャンブルが
My 99 percent sure-win gamble
has become one of pure luck!
単なる運否天賦 五分五分の
ギャンブルになっちまったが
It's now a 50-50 gamble.
しかし
引けば
But... if I manage to draw
the winning lot,
今ここで当たりを引けば
I'll still be safe!
どうあれ助かる
あるんだから
どこかに必ず当たりが
Because it's in here!
It's definitely
somewhere in here!
この中のどこかに
I'll take hold of
that luck right now!
その幸運を俺がここでつかむんだ
俺が
I'll...
神よ！
Oh, god!
えへ　えへへへへ
神よ！俺を祝福しろ！
Oh god, please grant me
this blessing!
Save me! Save me!
救え！救うんだ！
駄目
But it failed!
A second chance would
do you no good.
２度はいかんな　あはははは
わしのような王に
２度引かせてはいかん
A king like myself should not be
allowed to draw a second time.
２度もチャンスを与えられては
If you give me
a second chance,
I won't be able to stop myself
from drawing the winning lot!
引きたくなくても
引いてしまうではないか
あは　いひひ　ひひひひひひひひ
近づく夜明け
Daybreak approaches...
But Kaiji isn't allowed to
awaken from his nightmare yet!
だが悪夢はまだ
カイジに目覚めることを許さない
神はカイジと会長
どちらにほほ笑むのか
Will heaven smile upon Kaiji,
or the director?
カイジの祈りは天に届くか
Will Kaiji's prayers
ascend to heavens?
Will they reach at all?
届くのか
Next, Afterglow
次回｢残光｣